<elements>
    <info>
        <name>College of Flavor</name>
        <description>College of Flavor for Barbarians from The Tasty Lands of Silverplate</description>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name=" bard-flavor.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/silverplate-elements/refs/heads/main/bard-flavor.xml"/>
        </update>
    </info>
   <element name="College of Flavor" type="Archetype" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_BARD_FLAVOR">
    <supports>Bard College</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Bards of the College of Flavor have a deep understanding of what taste is and what it means to the foodfolk. They can channel their bardic performances to enrich the inner taste of the foodfolk; making their allies more powerful and bestowing curses on their enemies. </p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
            <div element="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_INTERRUPTED_FLAVORS" />
            <div element="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_FLAVOR_TASTIER" />
            <div element="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_FLAVOR_SPICOMANCER" />
            <div element="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_FLAVOR_INFLICTED_TASTES" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_INTERRUPTED_FLAVORS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_FLAVOR_TASTIER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_FLAVOR_SPICOMANCER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_FLAVOR_INFLICTED_TASTES" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Interrupted Flavors" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_INTERRUPTED_FLAVORS">
        <description>
            <p>When you join the College of Flavor at 3rd level, you gain the ability to interrupt a creature's flavor and bestow curses upon them. </p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration and target a creature that can see or hear you within 60 feet, interrupting its inner flavor. For the next hour, the next time that creature makes an attack roll, an ability check or saving throw, roll your Bardic Inspiration die and subtract the  number rolled from the creature's roll. </p>
            <p class="indent">Starting at 14th level, instead of rolling your Bardic Inspiration die to reduce a creature's roll, you can take the maximum instead. </p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Bardic Inspiration" action="Bonus Action">
            <description>As a bonus action, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration and target a creature that can see or hear you within 60 feet, interrupting its inner flavor. For the next hour, the next time that creature makes an attack roll, an ability check or saving throw, roll your Bardic Inspiration die and subtract the number rolled from the creature's roll.</description>
            <description level="14">As a bonus action, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration and target a creature that can see or hear you within 60 feet, interrupting its inner flavor. For the next hour, the next time that creature makes an attack roll, an ability check or saving throw, roll your Bardic Inspiration die and subtract the max possible roll from the creature's roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Tastier" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_FLAVOR_TASTIER">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 3rd level, your healing becomes more effective. As a bonus action, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration and mark a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you for 1 minute. Whenever you use a spell or another magical effect to restore hit points to the marked creature for the duration, it may roll your Bardic Inspiration die and gain a number of additional hit points equal to the result. </p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest to use it again. </p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Bardic Inspiration 1/Long Rest">
            <description>As a bonus action, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration and mark a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you for 1 minute. Whenever you use a spell or another magical effect to restore hit points to the marked creature for the duration, it may roll your Bardic Inspiration die and gain a number of additional hit points equal to the result.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Spicomancer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_FLAVOR_SPICOMANCER">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you can mend your allies and restore them to health. You can cast the lesser restoration spell a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier without expending a spell slot.</p>
            <p class="indent">Starting at 14th level, you can cast the greater restoration spell once using this feature without requiring a material component. </p>
            <p class="indent">You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast the lesser restoration spell without expending a spell slot.</description>
            <description level="14">You can cast the lesser restoration spell without expending a spell slot. You can cast the greater restoration spell once using this feature without requiring a material component.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Inflicted Tastes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SIVERPLATE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_FLAVOR_INFLICTED_TASTES">
        <description>
            <p>At 14th level, you can diminish your enemies' endurance by reshaping their tastes for a brief moment. </p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration and target a creature that can see or hear you within 120 feet of you. The creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or have vulnerability to one of the following damage types of your choice until the start of your next turn; acid, cold, fire, lightning, necrotic, poison, or radiant. If the target has immunity to the selected damage type, this feature has no effect on it. </p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Bardic Inspiration">
            <description>As a bonus action, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration and target a creature that can see or hear you within 120 feet of you. The creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or have vulnerability to one of the following damage types of your choice until the start of your next turn; acid, cold, fire, lightning, necrotic, poison, or radiant. If the target has immunity to the selected damage type, this feature has no effect on it.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>