<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Magic Rings</name>
        <description>Magic Rings from The Tasty Lands of Silverplate</description>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items-rings.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/silverplate-elements/refs/heads/main/items-rings.xml"/>
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Devouring Ring" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_DEVOURING_RING">
        <description>
            <p>According to legend, long ago in a now-forgotten village, there lived a tyrannical mayor. Everyone in the village hated the mayor since they lived in horrible conditions. However, the villagers were too scared to do anything because the mayor was a mighty spellcaster that could pulverize the entire village with a single spell.</p> 
            <p class="indent">One day, the youngest daughter of the village baker decided to do something, but none of the other foodfolk would help her. She knew she couldn't overthrow the mayor alone, so she begged the gods to help her. Alas, no gods heard her prayers. She prayed to the Cook and the Baker. Once again, her prayers went unanswered.</p>
            <p class="indent">Years went by, and one day the mayor came for the girl's family. Desperate to help them, she prayed to the Great Eater as a last resort, asking the entity to devour the mayor once and for all. The mayor laughed in disbelief, but at that very moment, a dark cloud erupted from the girl, smashing everything around her. The mayor gazed upon the young girl in fear while dark clouds gathered around her hand and formed an obsidian ring. Following her instinct, the baker's daughter rushed to the mayor, touched the tyrant's face, and the dark clouds reemerged from the ring in the form of a huge, sharp-toothed maw that devoured the mayor, ending the evil rule that had destroyed so many lives. Believing she had become a hero, the girl looked around expecting to find cheering foodfolk, but was met with the terrified looks on the villagers' faces, looking at her like she was some kind of monster. So she left the village she had saved, wearing the obsidian ring that was aptly named the devouring ring.</p>
            <p class="indent">This ring has 10 charges and it regains 1d8 + 2 expended charges daily at dawn. While wearing this ring, you can expend its charges to use the following features:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong><i>Devour (5 Charges).</i></strong> As an action, you can touch a creature and command the ring to devour it. If the creature you touched has 50 hit points or less, it is engulfed by a dark cloud maw and dies. Creatures devoured in this way can't be resurrected by any means.</li>
                <li><strong><i>Dark Clouds (4 Charges).</i></strong> You cast the circle of death spell (DC 15).</li>
                <li><strong><i>Fleeting Glimpse (2 Charges).</i></strong> You cast the misty step spell.</li>
                <li><strong><i>Eater’s Protection (1 Charge).</i></strong> You cast the shield spell.</li>
                <li><strong><i>Devour (5 Charges).</i></strong> As an action, you can touch a creature and command the ring to devour it. If the creature you touched has 50 hit points or less, it is engulfed by a dark cloud maw and dies. Creatures devoured in this way can't be resurrected by any means.</li>
            </ul>            
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="equippable">true</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="charges">10</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Red Ring of the Ox" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_RED_RING_OF_THE_OX">
        <description>
            <p>This ring infuses you with vigilance and energy, keeping you active and ready. You gain a +3 bonus to initiative while wearing it.</p>
            <p class="indent">The ring has 3 charges and regains all of its expended charges daily at dawn. You can expend 1 charge to cast the feather fall spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="equippable">true</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="charges">3</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="initiative:misc" value="3" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of Banana Peels" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_BANANA_PEELS">
        <description>
            <p>This golden magic ring looks like two bananas forming a circle. While wearing this ring, you gain a +1 bonus to saving throws.</p>
            <p class="indent">This ring has 6 charges and regains 3 expended charges daily at dawn. You can use an action to expend 1 charge and speak its command word. Once you do so, choose a point within 60 feet of you. A barrage of banana peels blast out from the chosen point, causing a30-foot radius centered on it to become difficult terrain. When a creature walks in this area for the first time on a turn, it must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or step on a banana peel and fall prone, taking 4d4 bludgeoning damage. The banana peels stay on the ground for 1 minute, then disappear.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="equippable">true</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="charges">6</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength:save:misc" value="1"/>
            <stat name="dexterity:save:misc" value="1"/>
            <stat name="constitution:save:misc" value="1"/>
            <stat name="intelligence:save:misc" value="1"/>
            <stat name="wisdom:save:misc" value="1"/>
            <stat name="charisma:save:misc" value="1"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of Mold Repelling" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_MOLD_REPELLING">
        <description>
            <p>These magical silver rings are used by many adventurers and warriors in their battles with mold creatures. It has a magic-infused glass sphere attached to it that repels molded monsters. The ring has 4 charges. It regains 1d4 expended charges daily at dawn. You can expend 1 charge as an action. When you do so, each creature that is considered "molded" (such as molded ones , mold oozes , molded giants) within 60 feet of you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or become repelled for 1 minute or until they take any damage. A repelled creature can't willingly move toward you while within 30 feet of you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="equippable">true</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="charges">4</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of Multiplication" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_MULTIPLICATION">
        <description>
            <p>Mostly used by lone adventurers, this silver ring makes an illusory copy of its wearer. It has 3 charges and it regains 1d4 - 1 (minimum 1) expended charges daily at dawn. You can expend 1 charge as a bonus action to create a translucent copy of yourself in an unoccupied space adjacent to you.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your copy has the same game statistics as you and carries the same magic items as you, except it has 10 hit points, and it can only make one weapon attack and do nothing else on its turn. Your copy wields the same weapons as you but they are not magical in any way. Your copy takes its turn immediately after you and at the end of its turn, it disappears.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="equippable">true</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="charges">3</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of Preservation" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_PRESERVATION_UNCOMMON">
        <description>
            <p>This golden ring has a little jar on it. When you wear it, you gain the following benefits according to the gemstone set within the jar.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>Ruby (Uncommon).</i></strong> You have advantage on saving throws made against being burnt or frozen.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="equippable">true</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of Preservation" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_PRESERVATION_RARE">
        <description>
            <p>This golden ring has a little jar on it. When you wear it, you gain the following benefits according to the gemstone set within the jar.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>Jade (Rare).</i></strong> You are immune to being burnt or frozen.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="equippable">true</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of Preservation" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_PRESERVATION_VERY_RARE">
        <description>
            <p>This golden ring has a little jar on it. When you wear it, you gain the following benefits according to the gemstone set within the jar.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>Sapphire (Very Rare).</i></strong> You are immune to being burnt, frozen, or tasteless. You also have advantage on Constitution saving throws.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="equippable">true</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of Time Mastery" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_TIME_MASTERY">
        <description>
            <p>This silver ring has twenty-four runes inscribed on it, representing each hour of the day. When you wear it, you can instinctively sense exactly what time it is. Also, you instinctively sense when it's time for something you are planning to do. For example, you sense when it's time to add water to a dish you're cooking, or you sense the right time to take your medication. Chefs use this item to cook better meals.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="equippable">true</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>
