<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Magic Items</name>
        <description>Magic Items from The Tasty Lands of Silverplate</description>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items-wonderous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/silverplate-elements/refs/heads/main/items-wonderous.xml"/>
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Apple of Immunity" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_APPLE_OF_IMMUNITY">
        <description>
            <p>This green magical orb looks like a glass apple ornament. While holding it, you can use your bonus action to speak its command word and cause the apple to hover around you. While the apple is hovering around you, whenever you take damage, you can use your reaction to take no damage instead. Once you do, you have immunity to the damage types prevented by the reaction until the next dawn. Whenever you are subjected to the said damage type, you regain 1d4 hit points instead of taking damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once used, the globe can't be used in this way again until the next dawn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Chopsticks of Extension" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_CHOPSTICKS_OF_EXTENSION">
        <description>
            <p>You can use the chopsticks to manipulate creatures from a distance. You can affect creatures within 300 feet that are also at least 120 feet away from you. As an action, you can use the chopsticks to hold a creature and move it. The target must succeed on a DC 10 Strength saving throw or it moves 10 feet in a direction of your choice. Large creatures have advantage on this saving throw, and Huge or larger creatures automatically succeed on it.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Cotton Candy Vase" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_COTTON_CANDY_VASE">
        <description>
            <p>Foodfolk of Silverplate use this vase both for decorative and culinary purposes.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you plant a seed inside, it grows twice as fast as its expected growing speed. The leaves of the plants growing inside this vase are cotton candy, although their fruit (if they bear any) is ordinary.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Common</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Fiery Oven Mitts" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_FIERY_OVEN_MITTS">
        <description>
            <p>These mitts look like regular oven mitts with red runes on them. When you wear these mitts, you are protected from fire. You have resistance to fire damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you make an unarmed attack while wearing the mitts, they blaze with fire and fury. Your successful unarmed attacks made with your hands deal an additional 1d6 fire damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="slot">hands</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Jell-Y-Suit " type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_JELL_Y_SUIT_1">
        <description>
            <p>This wondrous item is a tiny jelly bean with protective powers. As part of attuning to it, you must swallow the bean; the jelly bean stays inside you as long as you are attuned. If your attunement to this item ends, you throw up the bean.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>Sticky Skin (requires attunement).</i></strong> As an action, you can speak the command word to summon the jelly if you are not wearing any armor. When you do so, a thin layer of jelly with the flavor of your choice covers your skin. While wearing the jelly, you gain a bonus to AC according to the rarity of the jelly bean. You are not considered to be wearing armor while protected in this way. The jelly retreats back inside you if you put on armor or if you command it as a bonus action.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="ac:misc" value="1" equipped="[armor:none]" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Jell-Y-Suit" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_JELL_Y_SUIT_2">
        <description>
            <p>This wondrous item is a tiny jelly bean with protective powers. As part of attuning to it, you must swallow the bean; the jelly bean stays inside you as long as you are attuned. If your attunement to this item ends, you throw up the bean.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>Sticky Skin (requires attunement).</i></strong> As an action, you can speak the command word to summon the jelly if you are not wearing any armor. When you do so, a thin layer of jelly with the flavor of your choice covers your skin. While wearing the jelly, you gain a bonus to AC according to the rarity of the jelly bean. You are not considered to be wearing armor while protected in this way. The jelly retreats back inside you if you put on armor or if you command it as a bonus action.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="ac:misc" value="2" equipped="[armor:none]" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Jell-Y-Suit" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_JELL_Y_SUIT_3">
        <description>
            <p>This wondrous item is a tiny jelly bean with protective powers. As part of attuning to it, you must swallow the bean; the jelly bean stays inside you as long as you are attuned. If your attunement to this item ends, you throw up the bean.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>Sticky Skin (requires attunement).</i></strong> As an action, you can speak the command word to summon the jelly if you are not wearing any armor. When you do so, a thin layer of jelly with the flavor of your choice covers your skin. While wearing the jelly, you gain a bonus to AC according to the rarity of the jelly bean. You are not considered to be wearing armor while protected in this way. The jelly retreats back inside you if you put on armor or if you command it as a bonus action.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="ac:misc" value="3" equipped="[armor:none]" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Lettuce Cloak" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_LETTUCE_CLOAK">
        <description>
            <p>Woven from big, magical lettuce leaves, the lettuce cloak is a popular piece of gear among novice adventurers. Whenever you are targeted with a nonmagical weapon attack that you are aware of while wearing this cloak, you can use your reaction to increase your AC by 1 against the attack.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Common</set>
            <set name="slot">shoulders</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Mask of Eternal Might" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_MASK_OF_ETERNAL_MIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>These ornate masks are made of gold and covered with tiny gems of every color. They are incredibly alluring, emitting a captivating glow that draws in anyone who gazes upon them. These masks are both a blessing and a curse created by the ancient agents of the God of Trickery.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you wear this mask, all of your ability scores increase by 2. You don't need to eat, drink or sleep to sustain yourself. You can change the appearance of the mask as you please as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">Also, if you fail a saving throw, you can choose to succeed instead. Once used, the mask of eternal can't be used in this way again until the next dawn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>Curse.</i></strong> The curse is activated at a random time determined by the GM each week. When the curse is activated, you must succeed on a DC 20 Constitution saving throw. On a successful save, you postpone the curse until next week. On a failed save, your body is petrified and turns into a mass of hardened cake for 1d4+3 days; you cannot choose to succeed on the saving throw using the mask. During this time, you stay attuned to the item. If you stay petrified for seven days straight, the petrified condition on you becomes permanent.</p>
            <p class="indent">Only a wish spell cast on you ends the petrified condition. Once you are attuned to the item, you cannot end the attunement unless a remove curse spell is cast on you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="slot">head</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="2" />
            <stat name="dexterity" value="2" />
            <stat name="constitution" value="2" />
            <stat name="intelligence" value="2" />
            <stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
            <stat name="charisma" value="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Necklace of Temperature" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_NECKLACE_OF_TEMPERATURE">
        <description>
            <p>This golden necklace decorated with rubies and sapphires is crafted to protect the wearer against extreme temperatures. While wearing the necklace, you are immune to being burnt or frozen. Also, when you take fire or cold damage, you can choose to end the necklace's immunity effects and negate the damage as a reaction. If you do so, the necklace loses its magical properties until the next dawn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="slot">neck</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Pomegrenade" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_POMGRENADE">
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you can throw this pomegranate-shaped grenade up to 30 feet, causing it to explode upon colliding with a solid surface. If there is a creature at the point of impact, it must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 8d6 thunder damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. After the first explosion, thousands of little pomegrenades spawn from the bigger one and fly toward the adjacent spaces. Each creature within 10 feet of the explosion (except the one at the impact point) must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 12d4 thunder damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. This item is destroyed after it explodes.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">thunder</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Robe of Napkins" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_ROBE_OF_NAPKINS">
        <description>
            <p>This soft, white robe is designed to protect its wearer against unwanted accidents. While wearing this robe, any damage you take is dealt to the robe instead. The robe of napkins has 20 hit points, resistance to cold damage, and vulnerability to fire damage. When its hit points are reduced to 0, the robe withers away and reappears on you at the next dawn. Any excess damage carries over to you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="slot">shoulders</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Sprinkles of Wayfinding" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_SPRINKLES_OF_WAYFINDING">
        <description>
            <p>This small pouch contains 1d4 + 4 pinches of colorful magical sprinkles. You can use an action to scatter a pinch in front of you and speak the name of a place. The magical sprinkles form a line in the air leading to the named location. If there are multiple places with the same name, the sprinkles form a path toward the closest one. A single pinch can only form a 10-mile line. If the place is protected against divination spells such as the nondetection spell or is located in a different plane of existence than the one you are currently in, the scattered sprinkles fall to the ground and don't show a path. The magical line created by the sprinkles disappears after a day.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Strawberry of Resistance" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_STRAWBERRY_OF_RESISTANCE">
        <description>
            <p>At first glance, this magical red orb looks like a glass strawberry ornament. When you become attuned to it, it starts to hover around you and protect you against a single type of damage. Whenever you take damage, you can use your reaction to halve the damage. Once you do, you have resistance to one of the damage types (of your choice) that were halved by the reaction for the next hour.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once used, the globe can't be used in this way again until the next dawn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Sugarwater Incense" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_SUGARWATER_INCENSE">
        <description>
            <p>Made of herbs, spices, and pine-wood powder that has been soaked in Sugarwater Run for a year and dried, this item is considered sacred by the pilgrims of Silverplate.</p>
            <p class="indent">The incense itself is black; however, its sweet- smelling smoke has a soft pink color. When it is ignited, it creates a 20-foot-radius sphere of smoke centered on the burning incense. The sphere spreads around corners and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
            <p class="indent">Creatures who are exposed to the smoke for 1 minute must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be affected by it. A creature may also willingly choose to be affected by the incense.</p>
            <p class="indent">Affected creatures are immune to being charmed or frightened. Whenever an affected creature tries to deal damage, it must roll a d100. On a result of 51-100, the creature cannot take the action and its turn ends. Affected creatures have a +2 bonus to Wisdom checks.</p>
            <p class="indent">The effects end on a creature if it moves out of the area, or when the incense burns out at the end of 1 hour. If a creature succeeds on the saving throw, it is immune to the incense for the next 24 hours.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Sundae Cherry Piece" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_SUNDAE_CHERRY_PIECE">
        <description>
            <p>The cherry on top of the Sundae Mountain is a magical mystery placed upon the summit by the victorious sundae rebels. Its origin and the methods of its transportation to the highest peak are unknown. One bite from the enormous cherry is rumored to bestow eternal life and wisdom.</p>
            <p class="indent">The sundae cherry piece can't be targeted by any divination magic or perceived through magical scrying sensors.</p>
            <p class="indent">It takes 5 bites to consume one piece in its entirety. A creature gains the following features according to the number of bites it takes from the sundae cherry:</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>One Bite.</i></strong> All ability scores of the creature increase by 2, up to a maximum of 22.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>Two Bites.</i></strong> The creature becomes immortal. It doesn't age and can't be aged magically.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>Three Bites.</i></strong> The creature becomes immune to being charmed, frightened, and petrified, and it has immunity to all diseases.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>Four Bites.</i></strong> The creature doesn't need to eat, drink, sleep, or breathe.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>Five Bites.</i></strong> The creature dies and its body is destroyed. It can't be brought back to life by any means. Its soul is trapped within the cherry, the missing parts of which reappear at the top of Sundae Mountain.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="War Chef’s Apron" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_WAR_CHEFS_APRON">
        <description>
            <p>While you are wearing this magical white apron, you gain the following benefits:</p>
            <p class="indent">You have proficiency with kitchen weaponry.</p>
            <p class="indent">You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with kitchen weaponry.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your successful melee weapon attacks made with kitchen weaponry deal an extra 2d6 damage of one of the following damage types of your choice: acid, cold, fire, or poison.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="slot">misc</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_KITCHEN_WEAPONS" />
            <stat name="Cutting Knife:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Frying Pan:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Great Frying Pan:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Great Grater:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Great Oven Shovel:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Great Warfork:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Great Warspoon:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Oven Shovel:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Rolling Pin:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Throwing Pick:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Warfork:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="War Grater:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Warspoon:damage" value="1" />
            <stat name="Cutting Knife:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="Frying Pan:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="Great Frying Pan:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="Great Grater:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="Great Oven Shovel:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="Great Warfork:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="Great Warspoon:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="Oven Shovel:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="Rolling Pin:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="Throwing Pick:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="Warfork:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="War Grater:attack" value="1" />
            <stat name="Warspoon:attack" value="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Wet Wipes" type="Magic Item" source="Silverplate" id="ID_DRS_SILVERPLATE_MAGIC_ITEM_WET_WIPES">
        <description>
            <p>This item is found in magical boxes that each contain 1d8 + 2 wet wipes. You can pull out a wet wipe from its box as part of your movement, and once it's taken out of the box, it loses its magical properties at the end of an hour, becoming an ordinary wipe. As an action, you can use a wet wipe to clean a Medium or smaller foodfolk corpse, which immediately destroys the corpse, turning it into a stain on the wet wipe.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>